export const jsonData = {
        "data": [
          {
            "question": "Hello How are you can you help me hi hey",
            "answer": "Welcome to Nyaay Sahayak , How can i help you?.",
            "category": "Others"
          },
          {
            "question": "I lost my bike. What do I do?",
            "answer": "If your bike is lost, you should immediately file a First Information Report (FIR) at the nearest police station. Provide all the necessary details about the bike and the circumstances of its loss. Additionally, inform your insurance company about the incident.",
            "category": "Criminal Law"
          },
          {
            "question": "What are my rights if I am arrested?",
            "answer": "If you are arrested, you have the right to remain silent and consult with a lawyer. You should be informed of the charges against you. It is advisable not to make any statements without legal representation. Exercise your right to legal counsel during questioning.",
            "category": "Criminal Law"
          },
          {
            "question": "How can I create a valid will in India?",
            "answer": "To create a valid will in India, you should be of sound mind and sign the document in the presence of at least two witnesses. The witnesses should also sign the will. It is advisable to register the will to ensure its authenticity. Consulting with a lawyer is recommended to ensure compliance with legal requirements.",
            "category": "Family Law"
          },
          {
            "question": "What should I do if I'm facing workplace harassment?",
            "answer": "If you are facing workplace harassment, document the incidents and report them to your employer's internal complaints committee, if available. If the issue persists, you can file a complaint with the local sexual harassment ombudsman. Consult with a legal professional for guidance on the appropriate course of action.",
            "category": "Employment Law"
          },
          {
            "question": "How can I protect my intellectual property in India?",
            "answer": "To protect your intellectual property in India, you can register trademarks, copyrights, and patents with the relevant authorities. It is advisable to conduct thorough research and seek legal advice to ensure proper protection. Enforcing your intellectual property rights may require legal action in case of infringement.",
            "category": "Intellectual Property Law"
          },
          {
            "question": "What are the legal requirements for starting a business in India?",
            "answer": "To start a business in India, you need to register your company with the Ministry of Corporate Affairs, obtain the necessary business licenses, and comply with tax regulations. Consulting with a legal expert can help ensure that you meet all legal requirements.",
            "category": "Business Law"
          },
          {
            "question": "How can I dispute a property dispute with my neighbor?",
            "answer": "If you have a property dispute with your neighbor, attempt to resolve it amicably. If unsuccessful, consult with a lawyer and consider mediation. If needed, file a suit in the appropriate civil court. Providing evidence and documentation is crucial to supporting your case.",
            "category": "Civil Law"
          },
          {
            "question": "What are the legal implications of defaulting on a loan in India?",
            "answer": "Defaulting on a loan in India can lead to legal action by the lender. They may initiate recovery proceedings, which could include filing a case in the Debt Recovery Tribunal (DRT). It is advisable to communicate with the lender and explore options like loan restructuring before legal action is taken.",
            "category": "Financial Law"
          },
          {
            "question": "How can I protect my online business from cyber threats under Indian law?",
            "answer": "To protect your online business from cyber threats in India, implement robust cybersecurity measures. Comply with the Information Technology Act and rules, including data protection and privacy regulations. Regularly update security protocols and educate employees about cyber threats to minimize risks.",
            "category": "Cyber Law"
          },
          {
            "question": "What steps should I take in case of a motor vehicle accident?",
            "answer": "In the event of a motor vehicle accident, inform the nearest police station immediately and seek medical help for any injuries. Exchange information with the other party involved and gather evidence such as photographs. Notify your insurance company promptly and file a police report if required.",
            "category": "Criminal Law"
          },
          {
            "question": "How does the legal system handle child custody disputes in India?",
            "answer": "Child custody disputes in India are typically resolved based on the child's best interests. Family courts consider factors such as the child's age, health, and overall well-being. Parents may reach a mutual agreement or, if necessary, the court will make a decision based on the circumstances of the case.",
            "category": "Family Law"
          },
          {
            "question": "What are the legal rights of tenants in India?",
            "answer": "Tenants in India have various rights, including the right to a fair tenancy agreement, the right to peaceful possession of the property, and protection from unfair eviction. Tenants are also entitled to essential services. Familiarize yourself with the rent control laws applicable in your state for a comprehensive understanding of your rights.",
            "category": "Property Law"
          },
          {
            "question": "How can I protect my creative work under Indian copyright law?",
            "answer": "To protect your creative work under Indian copyright law, register your work with the Copyright Office. This registration serves as evidence in legal proceedings. Additionally, mark your work with the copyright symbol and your name. In case of infringement, consult with a lawyer to take appropriate legal action.",
            "category": "Intellectual Property Law"
          },
          {
            "question": "What are the legal implications of defamation in India?",
            "answer": "Defamation in India can result in civil and criminal liabilities. Defamatory statements can lead to a lawsuit for damages or a criminal complaint. Truth can be a defense in defamation cases, but it is essential to exercise caution to avoid legal consequences. Seek legal advice if facing or considering a defamation case.",
            "category": "Criminal Law"
          },
          {
            "question": "How can I legally terminate an employment contract in India?",
            "answer": "Terminating an employment contract in India must adhere to the terms of the contract and labor laws. Provide proper notice as specified in the contract or compensate the employee accordingly. Follow due process to avoid legal complications, and consult with legal professionals to ensure compliance with employment laws.",
            "category": "Employment Law"
          },
          {
            "question": "What legal options do I have if I receive a notice from the income tax department?",
            "answer": "If you receive a notice from the income tax department in India, promptly respond and provide the required information. Consult with a tax professional to understand the nature of the notice and address any concerns. Failure to comply with tax authorities can lead to penalties and legal consequences.",
            "category": "Tax Law"
          },
          {
            "question": "How can I protect my business trademarks in India?",
            "answer": "To protect your business trademarks in India, register them with the Controller General of Patents, Designs, and Trademarks. This provides legal protection and exclusive rights to use the trademarks. In case of infringement, you can take legal action against the infringer to enforce your rights.",
            "category": "Intellectual Property Law"
          },
          {
            "question": "What are the rights of consumers in India?",
            "answer": "Consumers in India have rights such as the right to safety, the right to be informed, the right to choose, and the right to seek redressal against unfair trade practices. Familiarize yourself with the Consumer Protection Act for detailed insights into consumer rights and remedies available.",
            "category": "Consumer Law"
          },
          {
            "question": "What is the process for resolving commercial disputes in India?",
            "answer": "Commercial disputes in India can be resolved through negotiation, mediation, arbitration, or litigation. The choice of method depends on the nature of the dispute and the agreements between the parties involved. Legal advice is recommended to determine the most appropriate approach.",
            "category": "Commercial Law"
          },
          {
            "question": "How can I navigate divorce proceedings in India?",
            "answer": "To navigate divorce proceedings in India, understand the grounds for divorce under Hindu, Muslim, Christian, or other personal laws. File a petition in the family court and consider options like mediation for an amicable settlement. Legal representation is advisable to guide you through the process and ensure your rights are protected.",
            "category": "Family Law"
          },
          {
            "question": "What are the legal procedures for adopting a child in India?",
            "answer": "Adopting a child in India involves obtaining eligibility clearance from the Central Adoption Resource Authority (CARA), completing a home study, and matching with a child. Legal formalities include petitioning the court for adoption and obtaining the adoption decree. It's important to comply with all legal requirements and procedures.",
            "category": "Family Law"
          },
          {
            "question": "What are the legal consequences of driving under the influence in India?",
            "answer": "Driving under the influence in India can result in penalties such as fines, imprisonment, or license suspension. Repeat offenses carry harsher punishments. It is a criminal offense under the Motor Vehicles Act. Legal representation can be sought if facing charges.",
            "category": "Criminal Law"
          },
          {
            "question": "How can I ensure legal compliance for my startup in India?",
            "answer": "To ensure legal compliance for your startup in India, adhere to regulations related to company registration, taxation, labor laws, intellectual property, and industry-specific standards. Regularly review legal requirements and consult with legal professionals to stay compliant and mitigate risks.",
            "category": "Business Law"
          },
          {
            "question": "What are the legal guidelines for setting up a non-profit organization in India?",
            "answer": "Setting up a non-profit organization in India involves registering under the Societies Registration Act, the Indian Trusts Act, or the Companies Act (Section 8). Comply with legal requirements for governance, tax exemptions, and reporting. Legal advice is recommended to navigate the process effectively.",
            "category": "Business Law"
          },
          {
            "question": "How can I legally resolve a family dispute in India?",
            "answer": "To legally resolve a family dispute in India, consider options like mediation or counseling for an amicable solution. If these fail, legal action through family courts may be necessary. Legal representation can help in negotiating settlements and ensuring fair proceedings.",
            "category": "Family Law"
          }
        ]
      }
      


// Data.js
// import  { useEffect, useState } from 'react';
// import { fetchData, getJsonData } from './datastore';

// export default function Data (){
//   const [jsonData, setJsonData] = useState(null);

//   useEffect(() => {
//     const fetchDataAndSetData = async () => {
//       await fetchData();
//       setJsonData(getJsonData());
//     };

//     fetchDataAndSetData();
//   }, []);
//   return jsonData;
// };
